（沖田十三）艦長日誌。
Captain's Log:
補修に立ち寄った惑星
レプタポーダにおいて→
On Leptapoda, the planet where we landed to resupply, we learned a surprising fact.
我々は
驚くべき事実を知ることになった。
ヤマトが向かうべき目的地→
The Yamato's final destination, Iscandar, which we'd thought a planet of hope,
希望の星であるはずの
イスカンダルと→
我々の敵　ガミラスは
二重惑星だったのだ。
is the twin planet of the enemy world, Garmillas.
両者の間には
我々のうかがい知れぬ→
The two share a connection about which we were not informed.
つながりがあるらしい。
彼らガミラスは　イスカンダルを→
The Garmillans hold Iscandar to be an object of worship.
崇拝の対象としていたのだ。
我々は　レプタポーダ収容所に→
We met with a high-ranking Garmillas official,
収監されていた　ガミラスの高官→
ディッツ提督との会談に臨んだ。
Admiral Ditz, who'd been imprisoned on Leptapoda.
現政権に
反旗を翻した彼らであったが→
He and his comrades were rebelling against the current leader of Garmillas.
互いの　いきさつを考えても
怨讐を超え→
But given our relationship, quickly putting differences aside was impossible.
すぐに
手を携えられるはずもなかった。
だが
ガミラスに関する有益な情報は→
That said, we did gain several useful pieces of information about Garmillas.
いくつか得ることができた。
指導者の名は　アベルト・デスラー。
Their leader's name was Abelt Desler.
総統として君臨し
その広大な星間国家を→
He ruled over his vast, interstellar empire with a terrible iron fist.
恐怖で支配しているのだ。
ディッツ提督たちは
人々を解放するために→
Admiral Ditz and his forces left for the other prison planets,
他の収容所惑星へと向かった。
intending to free the rest.
我々は　袂を分かつしかなかった。
We were forced to part ways.
しかし　共闘できないまでも→
But even if they would not fight with us, they left a liaison.
彼らは
連絡将校１名を残してくれた。
これは　未来に　希望を
つなぐことなのだと信じたい。
I would like to believe that this will lead to a future of hope.
なお
敵に拉致された本艦の船務長→
Furthermore, our ship's Operations Officer, kidnapped by the enemy,
森雪の生存が　確認された。
was confirmed to be alive.
彼女と接した
ドメル夫人の話では→
According to Mrs. Domel, who had made contact with her,
森雪は　ユリーシャとして…。
the Garmillans believed her to be Yurisha...
ううっ！　うぅ…。
うっ！　あぁ…。　あっ…。
Pause
まだだ…。　あと少し。
Not yet... Just a little longer.
（デスラー）ようこそ　ユリーシャ
我が大ガミラスに。→
Welcome, Yurisha, to Great Garmillas.
お迎えできて　光栄の至りだ。
I am honored to receive you.
（デスラー）まさか　私の顔を
忘れたわけではあるまいね？
You haven't forgotten me, have you?
（古代進）
一体　どうしたっていうんだ？
What's going on here?
（加藤）この女が　ファルコンに
乗せろと言って聞かないんだよ。
She's insisting on being allowed aboard a Falcon...
（メルダ）この男は
許可できないの一点張りだ。
And he keeps saying he can't allow it.
（加藤）当たり前だろ！
メルダ…　君の任務はなんだ？
Of course I can't!
Melda, what is your mission?
（メルダ）私は
連絡将校として乗艦している。
I am here as a liaison.
連絡将校としての任務に
ヤマト艦載機への→
Do your duties as a liaison involve one of the Yamato's fighters?
搭乗というのはあるのか？
（メルダ）ない。
They do not.
では　そういうことだ。
（メルダ）分かった　従おう。
There you have it, then.
Very well, I will obey.
（加藤）なっ！
古代の言うことなら聞くのかよ!?
So you'll listen to Kodai?
≪（篠原）
その子に乗せてもいい機体なら→
Don't we have something she could pilot?
≪あるんじゃないですか？
（加藤）うわっ！
（篠原）ほら
俺がバランで使ったやつ。　ふふっ。
There's the one I used on Balun.
（加藤）ああ～。
（メルダ）なんの話だ？
What are you talking about?
後は　任せた。
（加藤）って…　おい！→
I'll let you take care of it.
Hey! You're leaving?
投げっぱかよ!?→
おっ！
Squad 5, give a status report. After reporting, begin loading secondary armaments.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]（アナウンス）
当該作業員は　各班長に申告の後→
第二兵装　搭載作業に入れ。
（加藤）へへへへっ！
（メルダ）なるほど　鹵獲した機体か。
I see... A captured ship.
（玲）いいの？　同胞に　引き金を
引くことになるかもしれないのよ。
Are you sure about this? You'll be shooting at your people.
（メルダ）それは　お前たちしだいだ。
ん？
That will depend on you.
（メルダ）ヤマトの任務は
イスカンダルに向かうこと。→
The Yamato's mission is to reach Iscandar.
ガミラスへ行き
我々と戦うことではないはずだ。→
Not to go to Garmillas and fight.
それとも　復讐心から→
Or do you want to destroy us out of a desire for revenge?
私たちの星をたたきたい…→
それが　お前たちの本心か？
あっ　そんなこと…。
That isn't true...
（ユリーシャ）もう　ないよね？
あっ。
It isn't true anymore, right?
（メルダ　ガミラス語で）
Bud Iscandar.
（ユリーシャ）ねっ　ないよね？
Right? It isn't, right?
いいところで会ったわ。
あんたに会ったら→
I'm glad you're here... I've been meaning to ask you something!
ひと言
言おうと思ってたことがあるのよ。
（メルダ）おい　イスカンダルのお方を
あんた呼ばわりするな！
Hey, don't point your finger at one from Iscandar!
（ユリーシャ）ふふっ！　「あんた」でいい。
「あんた」は好きよ。
I don't mind. It doesn't bother me.
（メルダ）そんな…。
くっ！　なんで→
But...
イスカンダルとガミラスが
おんなじとこにあるって→
Why didn't you tell us Iscandar and Garmillas were at the same place?
黙ってたのよ！
はてな？　知ってたら来たかしら？
If you'd known, would you have come? Or wouldn't you have?
来なかったかしら？
ん？
（島）知ってたら
どうだったんだろう？→
What we'd have done if we'd known?
それでも　イスカンダルへ
行くって気持ちを保てたかな？→
Would we have still been able to maintain our desire to go to Iscandar?
たぶん　知らなかったから
ここまで来られたんだ。→
I think we made it this far because we didn't know.
まっ　お隣が
ガミラスだっていうのには→
But I was surprised that they're neighbors.
驚かされたけどね。→
メルダの話だと
森君は　ガミラス本星に→
Melda says that Mori is probably on the Garmillas home planet.
捕らわれてる可能性が
高いっていうじゃないか。→
たぶん　丁重に扱われてるよ。
She's probably being treated well.
ヤツらがまだ　彼女を
ユリーシャだと思い込んでるならな。
If they still believe she's Yurisha.
（森雪）ここの月は　大きいのね。
大きくて　きれい。
The moon here is big... Big and beautiful.
（ノラン）あれは　月ではありません。
えっ？
That isn't the moon.
（ノラン）ご存じないのですか？
あっ…。
You didn't know?
（ノラン）あれは　イスカンダルです。
That is Iscandar.
いつから？
When did you guess?
（ノラン）確信を持ったのは　今です。
I wasn't certain until just now.
そう…。　どうするの？
I see...
What will you do?
（ノラン）僕の任務は
あなたを　お守りすることです。
My duty is to protect you.
ん？
（ヒルデ）どうぞ。
Here.
ありがとう。
わあっ。
Thank you.
（セレステラ）下がっていいわ　ヒルデ。
You may leave, Hilde.
（ヒルデ　ガミラス語で）
Bud Iscandar.
（セレステラ）あの子は
外の坊やと同じ種族なの。→
That girl is the same race as the boy outside.
父親が　野蛮人の艦と戦って→
Her father died in battle with a barbarian ship. Called the Yamato, I believe.
命を落としたのよ。
ヤマトとかいう艦とね。
あっ。
私も同じ。
I wasn’t born on this planet, either.
生まれたのは　この星じゃない。
でも　あの子も私も
同じガミラス人なんだわ。
But she and I are both Garmillans.
あなたは
自分が何者か分かっていて？
Do you know who you are?
私は　イスカンダルのユリーシャ。
I am Yurisha of Iscandar.
（セレステラ）いいえ　違うわ。
はっ。
No, you are not.
（セレステラ）
今は　ガミラスのユリーシャよ。→
Now you are Yurisha of Garmillas. You are a bird in a cage.
あなたは　籠の鳥。→
イスカンダルに対する
駒にしかすぎない。
A mere pawn to use against Iscandar.
「あまねく星々
その知的生命体の救済」→
"The salvation of all intelligent life in the universe."
お姉様のご高説。→
Your sister's little speech.
ご立派よね。
自分では動かず他人を試すだけ。→
It's easy for her, isn't it? She does nothing but test others.
だけど　我らの総統は違う。
However, our leader is different.
銀河を超えた共栄圏を築き→
He's trying to build a civilization that spans galaxies.
それを実践なさろうとしている。
自分の手を汚そうとしない
あの女とは違うの。→
He isn't like that woman, who refuses to even dirty her own hands.
帝国の庇護の下で　人々は初めて→
Only under imperial protection can eternal peace be possible.
恒久の平和を享受できる。→
それこそが　真の救済であり→
That is true salvation.
彼には　それができるのよ。
And he can make it a reality.
（セレステラ）あなた　あの収容所に
立ち寄ったんですってね。→
I heard you stopped at that prison planet.
どうだった？
How was it?
ひどい場所だった。
（セレステラ）私ね→
It was awful.
When I was a child, I was sent there.
子供の頃　あそこにいたの。
えっ？
（セレステラ）ガミラス人じゃない
っていうだけでね。
Simply because I wasn't Garmillan.
（セレステラ）
そこから　あの人が　自分の手で→
And he saved us with his own hands.
救ってくださったのよ。→
他種族であった私たちを
ご自分の手で。
We, who were of another race.
愛してるの？
ん？
Do you love him?
ふっ…　あはははっ！
ごめんなさい。
イスカンダルの姫君にしては→
I'm sorry...
Only, that's such an odd question to hear from an Iscandarian princess.
随分と　下世話な物言いなので。
「愛してる」だなんて…。
Do I love him?
あっ　これ　メランの極上品よ。
This is the best tea, from Melan.
冷めないうちに　どうぞ。
Drink before it gets cold.
Today, we will attend General Domel's memorial ceremony.
（女官）本日は　ドメル将軍追悼式典に
ご列席いただきます。
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]（アナウンス）第５次植民計画会議は→
The 5th Colonization Planning Group meeting has been moved to Hall 6.
移民局　第６ホールに
議場が変更となりました。
My lord, the invincible Goer fleet's 3,000 ships are heading directly to Garmillas.
（ゲール）総統！　このゲール麾下の
無敵艦隊３０００隻は→
一路
ガミラスを目指しております。→
But it will take a minimum of two months.
しかし
あとふた月…　あとふた月は→
どうしても
かかってしまいます。→
We are working night and day to see you as soon as possible...
総統に　お目通りするために→
夜に日に継いで…。
もういい　ゲール君。
Enough, Goer... Just do your best.
頑張ってくれたまえ。
Yes, sir! Ghale Desler!
はっ！　ガーレ・デスラー！
The Yamato is entering our last line of defense.
（ヒステンバーガー）ヤマトは現在
絶対国防圏に侵入。→
It's knocking on the door of the Salezar System.
サレザーの玄関口まで
迫っています。
I'm told the Yamato has a gun with the power to destroy planets.
（ヴォッテル）聞けば　ヤマトは
惑星を破壊する威力を持った→
砲を持っているとか。
（ガデル）問題は　本土防衛の艦艇が→
The question is how to react, with our defensive fleets almost entirely absent.
ないに等しい状況で
どう対処するかです。
There is no need for worry. I've held a powerful fleet in reserve.
（ギムレー）
心配には及びません。
私のもとには
虎の子の艦隊が→
温存されています。→
The Imperial Guard, not the army, will defend its home planet.
本土防衛は　国軍に代わり→
我々　親衛隊が務めます。
My lord, I would like you to hear something.
総統　実は　ぜひ
お耳に入れたい件がございます。
What is it?
なんだね？
あの女→
That girl is not Yurisha.
ユリーシャなどではありません。→
I believe her to be a Terron.
おそらく　テロン人かと。
Are you certain?
（ヒス）それは間違いないのか？
I caught a glimpse of something.
垣間見えました。
ふん…　魔女。
Witch.
（ヒス）あぁ…。
それが何か問題なのかね？
Is that an issue?
Whether she's real is irrelevant.
本物かどうかなど
どうでもいいことなのだよ。
The Third Princess of Iscandar has approved the great unification.
イスカンダルの第三皇女が→
大統合を承認してくれた…→
And as long as the people believe that...
そして　そのことを
国民が信じてくれさえすればね。
I understand. You're correct.
（ヒス）
なるほど　おっしゃるとおりです。
It's time for the ceremony, everyone.
では諸君　儀式の時間だ。
Elk Domel, hero to the people and my dear friend.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]（デスラー）エルク・ドメル
国民の英雄であり　私の友。→
Your loss tears at my heart...
君を失ったことは　私にとって→
心臓をえぐられるに等しい。
I believe my beloved citizens feel the same way.
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]（デスラー）親愛なる臣民諸君も→
思いは同じであると信じている。→
But sadness will not bring him back.
だが
悲しんでも　彼は帰って来ない。→
What will fill the void he left? Only one thing...
その穴を埋めるのは何か…→
それは　ただ一つ→
Hope!
希望だ！　希望こそが→
Hope will heal our sadness, and guide the way to our future!
我々の悲しみを癒やし
未来を示してくれる。
I don't see Minister Talan.
（セレステラ）タラン長官の姿が
見えないようだけど。
Our lord has ordered him elsewhere.
（ガデル）兄は
総統の命で　別の場所にいます。
Indeed... They were such friends, I'm sorry to hear that.
それはそれは　ご親友だったのに→
残念ですね。
I shall give you hope!
私は　諸君らに希望を与えよう。
The dream of our people, our great destiny...
民族の悲願　我々の宿命→
Our great hope, the unification of Garmillas and Iscandar!
それは　ガミラスとイスカンダルの
大統合という希望だ。
In the distant past, our people were divided in two.
いにしえ　二つに分かれた民族が→
長き時を超え　今　再び→
Now it is time for us to become one again.
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]　一つとなるときが来たのだ。
The Third Princess of Iscandar, Yurisha, has approved this!
（デスラー）このことは
イスカンダル第三皇女→
ユリーシャ様の承認を
得ることができた。
（スターシャ）あっ！　ユリーシャ？
Yurisha?
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]（国民たち）わあ～～！
（拍手）
My people, let us move forward to our hope, the great unification!
諸君！　大統合という
希望に向かって　踏み出そう。
Let us move into the future!
未来に向かって　歩み出そう。
The endless march of Garmillas,
帝国の飽くなき前進こそ→
toward the future, is what my friend Domel would have desired!
我が友ドメルが
望んでいたことでもあるのだ！
（３人・ガミラス語で）
Ghale Garmillan!
（５人・ガミラス語で）
（一同・ガミラス語で）
Ghale Iscandar!
Ghale Desler!
Ghale Phuzeron!
This strategy you've proposed...
君が提出した
この戦術作戦案だが→
I cannot agree to the last part.
最後の項目は　認められない。
You're kidding, right?
（南部）えっ　冗談だよな？
Operations Officer Mori Rescue Plan
No, I cannot permit it.
いや　許可できない。
Why? But you...
（南部）
どうして？　だって　お前は…。
The Yamato's goal is Iscandar.
ヤマトの目的地は
イスカンダルだ。
Not Garmillas.
ガミラスじゃない。
（南部）本気なのか？→
A-Are you serious?
Then what happens to her? Do we let her die?
じゃあ　彼女はどうなる？
見殺しにするのか!?
Garmillas is right next to Iscandar.
（加藤）ガミラスは
イスカンダルと目と鼻の先だ。→
There's time for him to rethink it.
再考する余地は
あるんじゃないか？
To be honest...
（佐渡）正直言うと…→
Captain, you...
艦長　あんたは…。
I know.
分かっているよ。
But we've made it this far.
だが　ここまで来たんだ。
You're right.
（佐渡）そうじゃな…。
そうじゃった。
That's true.
Working with those Garmillans just because they're fighting their government...
（沢村）反政府だからって
あのガミラスと→
連帯しようなんて
上は　何考えてんだか。
I don't know what the higher-ups are thinking.
But isn't that Melda person an ally?
（宮澤）でも　メルダって人は
味方なんじゃないの？
You're being naive!
（小浜）甘いよ。
イスカンダルとガミラスが→
It's possible Iscandar and Garmillas are working together to trick us.
グルで　俺たち
だましてるってことだって…。
I don't want to consider it, but yeah.
（沢村）考えたくないけどな。
（吉田）おい　見ろよ。
Hey, look!
Celebrate reaching the Large Magellanic with a Magellan Parfait!
I see. He's doing that poorly?
（加藤）そうか…
おやじの具合　そんなに悪いのか。
（真琴）あっ！　ダメ　ダメ　ダメ！
守秘義務があるんだから。
No, no, no! We have a duty to confidentiality!
You can't tell everyone, Sabu!
ダメだよ　サブちゃん
みんなに　しゃべっちゃ。
I know that.
うん　分かってるよ。
You can't, Sabu...
≫（玲）ダメだよ～　サブちゃん。
あっ…。→
うわぁ～！　あっ　あぁ…。
We'll keep the confidentiality.
（玲）
守秘義務は守ります。　にぃ～！
H-Hey...
（加藤）
おっ　おい！　ご…　誤解するなよ！
D-Don't get the wrong idea!
It's the wrong idea?!
えっ！　誤解なの？
はあ～!?
She called him "Sabu."
「サブちゃん」だって…。　あぁ～あ。
Do you not have one? Someone like that?
（ユリーシャ）君は　いないの？
いい人　いないの？
No one's asking you!
（玲）余計なお世話よ！
I do.
私は　いるよ。
（玲・メルダ）ええ～!?
Eh?! Who? Is it Kodai?
（玲）誰？
（メルダ）まさか　古代では？
No way... Not a chance. S-So who is it?
（玲）
それはない。　断じてない。　で　誰？
They are not here.
（ユリーシャ）ここには　いない。
Oh, they're on Iscandar?
（玲）そっか　イスカンダルに。
（メルダ）失礼だぞ　ずけずけと。
You're being rude, asking so many questions!
Won't you eat, Melda?
メルダは食べないの？
はっ…。
It's good.
（ユリーシャ）おいしいよ。
あっ　その…　自分は…。→
Well... I...
Hey, are you sure this is food?
おい
ほんとに　これは食べ物なのか？
Magellan Parfait. It's a popular dessert on board.
（玲）マゼランパフェ
うちの人気スイーツです。
You won't eat?
食べないの？
そっ　そんなことは…。
O-Of course!
（メルダ）んんっ！　ん？
Well?
（玲）どうよ？
（メルダ）こんなものが→
I can't believe such a thing existed in this universe...
宇宙にあったとは…。
（玲）はい？
Isn't that right?
I'm very moved right now!
（メルダ）私は今　感動している！
You have some on you.
付いてる。
ん？
Anyway, did you ask about that other thing?
それはそうと
例の件　頼んでもらえたか？
えっ？　まあね。　ふふっ。
Yeah, I did.
She insists it has to be this color...
（土岐）それが
どうしても　この色でって。
Huh...
（榎本）そりゃどうも…。→
I don't understand women...
女の子ってなぁ　分からんな～。
（土岐）ですねぇ。
Yeah.
（玲）ふふふっ！
Is something funny?!
（メルダ）何か　おかしいのか!?
You're so cute, Melda.
メルダは　かわいいね。
You honor me!
（メルダ）そんな…　もったいないです。
You really are cute.
（玲）ほんと　かわいいね。
（メルダ）お前は言うな！
You don't get to say it!
（玲）ねえ　さっきの話だけど。
Getting back on topic...
Listen to me!
（メルダ）人の話を聞け！
Is it true you have someone waiting for you on Iscandar?
ほら　イスカンダルに
待ってる人がいるって→
ほんと？
あっ。
When I get back, there is something I must tell them.
戻ったら
伝えなければならないことがある。
You're going to confess that you like them?
えっ！　それって告白？
おい！
Hey!
It is not my decision...
（ユリーシャ）決めるのは　私じゃない。
Operations Officer Mori Rescue Plan
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　キィーン…（ハウリング）
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]（真田）副長より達する。→
Message from the XO.
At shipboard time 1100, we will enter warp.
本艦は　艦内時間１１００に
ワープに入る。→
Everyone, stand by in type-2 space gear.
総員　第二種空間装備にて待機。
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　ウウー　ウウー…（警告音）
Rescue
≫ガン！
（南部）うわっ！
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　ウウー　ウウー…
It's still at eighty percent functionality.
（タラン）こちらは　まだ
８０％の稼働率です。→
I believe it's a bit early to use it.
使用するのは　時期尚早かと。
I don't mind, Talan. As long as we can use it.
かまわないよ　タラン。
あれが使えさえすればね。
My lord, if I may speak freely, this facility was meant for when we moved the capital.
（タラン）
恐れながら　総統　この施設は→
来るべき遷都に備えたものです。→
It wasn't intended for use against the Yamato.
本来　ヤマトに対するものでは…。
あっ。
I said I don't care.
（デスラー）
私は　かまわないと言ったのだよ。
Zar Belk.
ザー・ベルク。
The Yamato is coming... They're safe!
（心の声）≪ヤマトが来る。
無事だったんだ≫
They've come a long, long way.
はるばる
ここまで　やってきたのだ。
We must greet them properly.
その労に報い
丁重に　出迎えなくてはね。
You may stay here and watch.
君も　ここで見ているといい。
What is about to happen?
何を始めるおつもりです？
A war.
戦争だよ。
Crew, Earth is 160,000 light years behind us.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　諸君　地球は　我々のはるか後方
１６万光年にある。
But that is just a number.
だが　そんなものは
ただの数字にすぎない。
Earth is right behind us!
地球は　すぐ後ろにある。
It is right behind us, awaiting your return.
後ろにあって
諸君らの帰りを待っている。
We will soon reach our final objective, the Salezar System.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　ヤマトは
間もなく　最終目的地のある→
サレザー恒星系に到達する。→
But the enemy's home planet is there, as well.
しかし　敵の本星もまた
同じ星系にある。→
It is both our goal and also enemy territory.
そこは目的地であり
敵地でもあるのだ。→
But we will choose the path to Iscandar.
だが　我々は
イスカンダルへの道を選ぶ。→
Because that is where hope lies.
それは
そこに希望があるからだ。→
And because the Earth is behind us, awaiting our return with that hope.
そして　すぐ後ろにある地球が
その希望を手に→
ヤマトが帰るのを
待っているからだ。
The Yamato will now enter warp,
ヤマトは　これよりワープに入る。
our last major warp before Iscandar.
イスカンダルへ向けた
最後の大ワープだ。
All crew will maintain combat status 1 and prepare for warp!
総員　第一種戦闘配置のまま→
ワープに備えよ。
All crew to combat status 1.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]（南部）総員　第一種戦闘配置。→
Repeat: All crew to combat status 1.
総員　第一種戦闘配置。
Engines to full.
機関最大！
Enter warp!
ワープに入れ！
Entering warp!
（島）ワープに入る。
That's Epidora, fifth planet in the Salezar System.
（メルダ）
サレザー系第５惑星のエピドラだ。
There is a twin planet in the fourth orbit.
（太田）
第４惑星軌道に　二連星を確認。
Magnify.
拡大投影。
（相原）これが　イスカンダル。
That's Iscandar?
But next to it...
（南部）だが　隣は…。
No ships on cosmo radar.
（百合亜）
コスモレーダーに　感なし。→
No enemies in a radius of fifty light seconds.
半径５０光秒以内に
敵影　認められず。
It's quiet.
（島）静かだ。
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　１０　９　８　７→
６　５　４→
３　２　１→
０！
≫ビシューーン!!
あっ！　ガミラス→
High energy readings at point L-1 between Garmillas and Iscandar!
イスカンダルのポイントＬ１に
高エネルギー反応！
ん!?
Episode 22: The Planet That We Head For
The enemy unleashes the light of despair upon the Yamato.
Will the Yamato be blown apart just as it reaches its destination?
Overcome this deadly peril and advance, Yamato!
Your goal is the enemy's heart: Desler's Palace.
Next time: One Man's War.
There are 210 days left before humanity is extinct.
緊迫するシリア情勢。
アメリカのオバマ大統領は３１日
シリアへの軍事介入について、
議会の承認を得た後に実施すると
述べた。